<?xml version="1.0" standalone="yes"?>
<Articles>
  <Article>
    <AritleID>1</AritleID>
    <ArticleTitle>How keep the environment clean</ArticleTitle>
    <ArticleDesc>With environmental issues like water contamination, pollution, and climate change, it’s natural to look for ways we can reverse the damage to our planet and keep our environment clean. Many of us think we’re too small to make a difference, but when enough of us take action, we’ve seen the positive results we can create,.Today we’re looking at the steps – big and small – you can take to keep our environment clean and safe. </ArticleDesc>
  </Article>
  <Article>
    <AritleID>2</AritleID>
    <ArticleTitle>Greenhouse Effect</ArticleTitle>
    <ArticleDesc>The greenhouse effect is the process by which radiation from a planet's atmosphere warms the planet's surface to a temperature above what it would be without its atmosphere.[1][2]

If a planet's atmosphere contains radiatively active gases (i.e., greenhouse gases) they will radiate energy in all directions. Part of this radiation is directed towards the surface, warming it.[3] The intensity of the downward radiation – that is, the strength of the greenhouse effect – will depend on the atmosphere's temperature and on the amount of greenhouse gases that the atmosphere contains.

Earth’s natural greenhouse effect is critical to supporting life. Human activities, mainly the burning of fossil fuels and clearing of forests, have strengthened the greenhouse effect and caused global warming

The term "greenhouse effect" arose from a faulty analogy with the effect of sunlight passing through glass and warming a greenhouse. The way a greenhouse retains heat is fundamentally different, as a greenhouse works mostly by reducing airflow so that warm air is kept inside</ArticleDesc>
  </Article>
  <Article>
    <AritleID>3</AritleID>
    <ArticleTitle>How is Earth a greenhouse? </ArticleTitle>
    <ArticleDesc>Earth's atmosphere does the same thing as the greenhouse. Gases in the atmosphere such as carbon dioxide do what the roof of a greenhouse does. During the day, the Sun shines through the atmosphere. Earth's surface warms up in the sunlight. At night, Earth's surface cools, releasing the heat back into the air. But some of the heat is trapped by the greenhouse gases in the atmosphere. That's what keeps our Earth a warm and cozy 59 degrees Fahrenheit, on average.</ArticleDesc>
  </Article>
  <Article>
    <AritleID>6</AritleID>
    <ArticleTitle>Why can't we just plant more trees? </ArticleTitle>
    <ArticleDesc>You might well wonder, because, after all, trees—like all plants—take in carbon dioxide and give off oxygen.

Well, that might help a little. But, instead of planting more forests, some people are cutting them down and burning them to make more farm land to feed the growing human population.

The ocean also absorbs a lot, but not all, of the excess carbon dioxide in the air. Unfortunately, the increased carbon dioxide in the ocean changes the water, making it more acidic. Ocean creatures don't like acidic water. The bleached out, unhealthy coral in this picture is just one example of what acidic water can do.
</ArticleDesc>
  </Article>
  <Article>
    <AritleID>5309</AritleID>
    <ArticleTitle>Sri Lanka launches hotline for garbage collection in Colombo</ArticleTitle>
    <ArticleDesc>July 05, 2017 – Sri Lanka’s Provincial Councils and Local Government Ministry has launched a hotline for people to make complaints about garbage collection in the Colombo Municipal area.

The ministry has set up a special unit called the “National Task Force for Management of Waste” which will be manned by the tri-forces and an environmental police unit.

The hotlines are : 011-3301445 and 011-5993755.

“People can call and complain about issues pertaining to waste collection in their respective areas,” a senior official in the ministry said.

“For the moment the unit will first focus on the Western Province which is currently facing issues with garbage collection and later the service will be expanded to other parts.”

According to available data the Western Province alone produces around 60 percent of the nation’s waste, with 3,400 metric tons produced per day.

About 86 percent of waste is dumped in the open with only about 6 percent of this made into compost and about 4 percent of it recycled.</ArticleDesc>
  </Article>
</Articles>